Dupont Circle - "Slices of the Pie" Oral History Project OHP010
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Dupont Circle - "Slices of the Pie" Oral History Project
1984-1985
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Cherkasky, Mara
OHP010
3 Linear feet
3 Boxes
Arrangement
Series 1: Transcripts Materials in this series include transcripts for all interviews. Series 2: Interviews Materials in this series include master and patron access copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are two copies for all audio recordings except 10-08, 10-12, and 10-18.
Biographical / Historical
Mara Cherkasky is a historian and author. She earned a Master's of Arts from The George Washington University and a Bachelor of Arts from the University of Wisconsin at Madison.
Custodial History
Mara Cherkasky conducted these interviews between 1984 and 1985, and donated the tapes and transcripts to the Library in the late 1980s. There is no deed of gift for this collection, but all interviewee releases are granted to the Library.
Scope and Contents
Between 1984 and 1985, Mara Cherkasky (then a graduate student at The George Washington University) conducted 35 oral history interviews with longtime Dupont Circle residents. The interviews were conducted as a part of her master's thesis research about the changes to the Northwest, D.C. neighborhood. Her thesis is entitled "Slices of the Pie: Black and White Dupont Circle from the 1920s to the 1950s." Topics include Dupont Circle from the 1920s to the 1950s, childhood experiences, work and life experiences, and segregation.
Oral History; Dupont Circle (Washington, D.C.); Neighborhoods; Segregation
- Series 1: Transcripts
  Scope and Contents
  Materials in this series include transcripts for all interviews.
  - Beatrice Aitchison, 1984 April 11 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Gertrude Blackistone, 1984 April 4 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bernice Blakely and Annette Credle, 1984 June 21 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lavinia Broughton, 1984 October 5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mary and Alice Brown, 1984 October 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Inez Browne, 1984 November 16 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Frank Colbert, 1984 September 28 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Emma Crudup, 1984 November 7 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Lee S. Daub, 1985 January 13 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ernest Eilard, 1984 November 28 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Hortense Fitzgerald, 1984 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Helen Gentry, 1984 April 16 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Elizebeth Gibson, 1984 April 30 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Nathaniel Hill, 1984 October 17 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Dorothy Howard, 1984 April 5 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Harry Howlett, Mary Tuthill, Madelene Johnston, John Johnston, and Mara Cherkasky, 1984 September 2 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Harriet Hubbard, 1984 September 17 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Joseph Johnson, 1984 April 1 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Corinne McCampbell, 1984 July 2 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Catherine McCarron, 1984 March 4 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Lewis Marshall, 1984 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - John Osborne, 1984 May 17 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Artie Parlor, 1984 October 9 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Gladys Roberts, 1984 March 14 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Eunice E. Thompson-Shepherd, 1984 September 21 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Naomi Wallace and Ruth Long, 1985 January 21 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Ruby Wilfork, 1984 May 11 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Series 2: Interviews
  Materials in this series include master and patron access copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are two copies for all audio recordings except 10-08, 10-12, and 10-18.
  - Beatrice Aitchison, 1984 April 11 (Box 2, Folder 10-01)
  - Gertrude Blackistone, 1984 April 4 (Box 2, Folder 10-02)
  - Bernice Blakely and Annette Credle, 1984 June 21 (Box 2, Folder 10-03)
  - Lavinia Broughton, 1984 October 5 (Box 2, Folder 10-04)
  - Mary and Alice Brown, 1984 October 1 (Box 2, Folder 10-05)
  - Inez Browne, 1984 November 16 (Box 2, Folder 10-06)
  - Frank Colbert, 1984 September 28 (Box 2, Folder 10-07)
  - Emma Crudup, 1984 November 7 (Box 2, Folder 10-08)
  - Lee S. Daub, 1985 January 13 (Box 2, Folder 10-09)
  - Ernest Eilard, 1984 November 28 (Box 2, Folder 10-10)
  - Hortense Fitzgerald, 1984 May 24 (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
  - Helen Gentry, 1984 April 16 (Box 2, Folder 10-12)
  - Elizebeth Gibson, 1984 April 30 (Box 2, Folder 10-13)
  - Nathaniel Hill, 1984 October 17 (Box 2, Folder 10-14)
  - Dorothy Howard, 1984 April 5 (Box 2, Folder 10-15)
  - Harry Howlett, Mary Tuthill, Madelene Johnston, John Johnston, and Mara Cherkasky, 1984 September 2 (Box 2, Folder 10-16)
  - Harriet Hubbard, 1984 September 17 (Box 2, Folder 10-17)
  - Joseph Johnson, 1984 April 1 (Box 2, Folder 10-18)
  - Corinne McCampbell, 1984 July 2 (Box 2, Folder 10-19)
  - Catherine McCarron, 1984 March 4 (Box 2, Folder 10-20)
  - Lewis Marshall, 1984 May 25 (Box 2, Folder 10-21)
  - John Osborne, 1984 May 17 (Box 3, Folder 10-22)
  - Artie Parlor, 1984 October 9 (Box 3, Folder 10-23)
  - Gladys Roberts, 1984 March 14 (Box 3, Folder 10-24)
  - Eunice E. Thompson-Shepherd, 1984 September 21 (Box 3, Folder 10-25)
  - Naomi Wallace and Ruth Long, 1985 January 21 (Box 3, Folder 10-26)
  - Ruby Wilfork, 1984 May 11 (Box 3, Folder 10-27)